When MCP was first announced, initially
it was kind of too oriented for
developers. Now, we see is absolutely
every level company size from startup
all the way up to regulated industry
like banks and financial services are
starting to realize that if they're
going to give their employees access to
AI for productivity, the logical next
step is to also have that AI be
connected to some of their internal
workplace applications and services. So,
I think like it's it's definitely
escaped the kind of developer chambers
and is now in the real world.
>> How far are we from people being able to
truly trust, you know, what they see
from MCP servers? And what in your
experience is that level of trust in the
industry?
>> You can't really trust
any just off-the-shelf MCP server you
find. And this is coming from somebody
who runs an MCP servers who I would of
course love everybody to trust us, but
it's just you can't trust anything um
because you don't know what exactly is
happening behind the scenes. What's What
actually happens when you call that tool
um
with whatever data the model has decided
to extract from your prompt and send off
to that MCP server.
Um so, there there is a substantial
challenge so to um you know, figure out
with regard to trust. But I think that
the first step is actually just using
the MCP servers that are from the
providers themselves. Just like you
would trust any normal
uh HTTP API that you interface with to
you know, a service like Spotify or
PayPal or Google
um
they should and hopefully will at some
point provide a you know, first-party
MCP server
um because that that that does alleviate
some of the you know, trust concerns.
>> Yeah, absolutely. I think it I think
it's I'd love to talk about the
difference between almost managed versus
self-hosted um
MCP servers here. If I'm if I'm
self-hosting myself, I'm running this
maybe even locally, for example, the
risk is much much lower, but I have to
trust the the the MCP server is is, you
know, doing the right things with the
data I'm passing it and and and handling
that correctly.
But managed servers, managed MCP
servers, there there there's, you know,
a bunch of other,
you know, valid things that that that
will offer us as well that our laptops
and and local machines
just can't do at scale. Talk us through
what that, you know, when a developer
thinks, "Okay, should I go to that
remote or should I host this locally or
do it on my machine and STD
you know,
STDIO kind of
spin-off of an MCP server?" What is What
is the right choice when?
>> I'm more and more convinced that
standard IO MCP servers are never the
right choice. Well, unless you're
writing yourself, the risk is
substantial and the risks are now
um
at the level of your machine with the
same privileges that you as the user of
your machine have.
And so, if if if that MCP server is just
running on your laptop, it has the
ability to read your environment
variables, it has the ability to call
the network in any fashion it likes
using any protocol and any tools it
likes. It has the ability to read and
write to your file system and this is
like kind of the, you know, red alert
highest severity problem uh that a user
of an MCP server will face. So, the
movement of these MCP servers up to
managed endpoints remotely or in the
cloud um removes a whole layer of
security risk that is down at the
endpoint, down at the client computer,
the user's machine. However, there are
definitely times where you kind of need
to have a standard IO MCP server. If
you're largely working with developer
tools and they need to call a CLI that's
on your machine or if your code project
is only local to your machine and an MCP
server is operating on diagnostics from
your IDE or something like that, you
can't get that up in the cloud unless
you're using some, you know, kind of
managed cloud code generating platform.
I think you guys probably know a couple
of good ones there. So, I I I I think
largely, you know, the remote MCP
servers are the more secure ones. Um but
you also need to trust that the endpoint
is authentic and you need to be able to
connect to it and authenticate to it. Um
so, I don't think there's a a, you know,
hard and fast rule as to like which is
the better,
you know, transport to use for an MCP
server, whether it be standard IO or
remote. I think this is very
situationally relevant and say, "Okay,
well, what what kind of data am I using?
Where does the data live? What is the
authentication, you know, what is the
security risk?" And, you know,
the reason all these transports exist is
because they have, you know, their own
time and place to use them. Um but I
think we're moving away from a local
standard IO based MCP server that
executes on the user's machine um
just because there's there's there are
more implementations of MCP servers
remotely
um
and I think those are far easier to
trust. Um
now,
running an MCP server remotely
in your own infrastructure versus
just connecting to a remote URL that is
provided over the internet uh are also
two different things. You can implement
an MCP server that wraps an API because
the API provider themselves don't
provide an MCP server and absolutely run
that yourself, um host it in your own
network and connect to it through um you
know, your
infrastructure. Um
we see many many companies deciding to
move in that direction just for the
control and the transparency over what
tools are you know being connected to by
MCP clients that their teams are using.
Um, and to plug a product, we do
actually have kind of a self-hosted MCP
platform um
that provides this level of
transparency, auditability, security. Go
Turbo MCP.
Um, and this is largely a learning um
from providing mcp.run. Um, large
organizations and folks who are more
concerned about security aren't going to
trust a public proxy to take this MCP
traffic from a MCP client and transmit,
you know, whatever sensitive information
from a database or a SaaS product
through a public proxy up to its
upstream service.
Um, and so in order to kind of satisfy
that need of controlling that proxy and
owning that traffic, um you know, we did
build a self-hosted version of mcp.run.
But this is a little bit more for kind
of a larger kind of more
security-oriented enterprise customer.
For individuals, you know, using public
proxies is still fine. Um, but you're
but you're definitely taking on a little
bit of risk just to trust that entity
that you're not going to
send off my Notion page data or my
calendar data up to some, you know,
advertising service or
um if you get hacked, then well, you
have all my auth tokens and all of the
you know, plain text data that was
extracted from you know, my email um
that's maybe sitting inside your
database somewhere.